Guide to the Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts Videorecordings
Stanford University Library
Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts videorecordings
1999-2006
V0251
Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts.
1.5 Linear feet
(31 videotapes)
Lecturers represented in this collection include Svetlana Alpers (art history), Elaine Scarry (human rights and the humanities), Lynn Hunt (the novel and human rights), Hazel V. Carby (racializing subjects in post-World War II Britain), Wendy Doniger (self-imitation in ancient India, Shakespeare and Hollywood), Merce Cunningham (in conversation with John Rockwell, dance critic for the NY Times), and Douglas R. Hofstadter (analogy as the core of cognition).
Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives Stanford University Libraries 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/spc.html
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: tapes that are not VHS will need to be reformatted prior to use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts brings the most distinguished scholars, artists, and critics of our time to the Stanford University campus for lectures, seminars, panel discussions, and a variety of related interactions with faculty, students, and the community at large.
Description of the Collection
Lecturers represented in this collection include Svetlana Alpers (art history), Elaine Scarry (human rights and the humanities), Lynn Hunt (the novel and human rights), Hazel V. Carby (racializing subjects in post-World War II Britain), Wendy Doniger (self-imitation in ancient India, Shakespeare and Hollywood), Merce Cunningham (in conversation with John Rockwell, dance critic for the NY Times), and Douglas R. Hofstadter (analogy as the core of cognition).
Access Terms
Alpers, Svetlana.; Carby, Hazel V.; Cunningham, Merce.; Doniger, Wendy.; Hofstadter, Douglas R., 1945-; Hunt, Lynn Avery.; Rockwell, John.; Scarry, Elaine.; Stanford Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Videos
  - Presidential Lectures: Aesthetic Autonomy in the Age of Late Capitalism with Frederic Jameson, January 25, 1999., V251.1; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures: No Future? Literature and Cultural Politics with Beatriz Sarlo, February 22, 1999., V251.2; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Series: Presidential Lectures: Sleep of Reason Produces… with Alexander Nehamas, March 8, 1999., V251.3; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures: What Are We Looking For? Expectations in Art History with Svetlana Alpers, November 8, 1999., V251.4; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Human Rights and the Humanities, February 12, 2001., V251.5; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Human Rights and the Humanities (Spivak), February 12, 2001. (copy 1 of 2), V251.6; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Human Rights and the Humanities (Spivak), February 12, 2001. (copy 2 of 2), V251.7; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Human Rights and the Humanities, February 21, 2001. (copy 1 of 2), V251.8; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 1)
  - Presidential Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Human Rights and the Humanities, February 21, 2001. (copy 2 of 2), V251.9; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Stanford Humanities: Elaine Scarry lecture, February 25, 2002, VHS., V251.10; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Lynn Hunt: Stanford Humanities Department Presidential Speakers Series, SVHS MASTER copy, April 8, 2002. (master copy), V251. 11; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Lynn Hunt: Stanford Humanities Department Presidential Speakers Series, April 8, 2002. (copy 1 of 3), V251.12; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Lynn Hunt: Stanford Humanities Department Presidential Speakers Series, April 8, 2002. (copy 2 of 3), V251.13; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Lynn Hunt: Stanford Humanities Department Presidential Speakers Series, April 8, 2002. (copy 3 of 3), V251.14; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Humanities Center Presidential Endowed Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Dr. R. L. Brown -- Scholarship and Imagination: The Study of Late Antiquity, January 27, 2003. (copy 1 of 3), V251.15; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Humanities Center Presidential Endowed Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Dr. R. L. Brown -- Scholarship and Imagination: The Study of Late Antiquity, January 27, 2003. (copy 2 of 3), V251.16; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Humanities Center Presidential Endowed Lectures in the Humanities and Arts: Dr. R. L. Brown -- Scholarship and Imagination: The Study of Late Antiquity, January 27, 2003. (copy 3 of 3), V251.17; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Brown Presidential Series, January 27, 2003., V251.18; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 2)
  - Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center Events, Monday, November 3, 2003, 7PM: “Child of Empire: Racializing Subjects in Post World War II Britain”, Hazel V. Carby, November 3, 2003. (copy 1 of 3), V251.19; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center Events, Monday, November 3, 2003, 7PM: “Child of Empire: Racializing Subjects in Post World War II Britain”, Hazel V. Carby, November 3, 2003. (copy 2 of 3), V251.20; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center Events, Monday, November 3, 2003, 7PM: “Child of Empire: Racializing Subjects in Post World War II Britain”, Hazel V. Carby, November 3, 2003. (copy 3 of 3), V251. 21; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Wendy Doniger, February 23, 2004., V251.22; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 2)
  - Appiah Pres. Lecture, November 1, 2004. [Supposedly Tape 1 of 2; Tape 2 not present], V251. 23; 1 videotape (MiniDV) (Box 2)
  - Merce Cunningham Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center, March 9, 2005, V251.24; 1 videotape (Betacam SP L) (Box 3)
  - Merce Cunningham Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center, March 9, 2005., V251.25; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Stanford Presidential Lecture Video, 15 Minutes, Cunningham Dance Foundation [no date given; probably March 9, 2005]., V251.26; 1 videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Merce Cunningham Presidential Lecture, Stanford Humanities Center, March 9, 2005., V251.27; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 3)
  - Stanford Humanities Merce Cunningham, March 9, 2005., V251.28; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 3)
  - Presidential Lecture with Carolyn Abbate, May 2, 2005., V251.29; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 3)
  - Presidential Lecture D.R. Hofstadter, February 6, 2006. [Tape #1, but Tape #2 not present], V251. 30; 1 videotape (DVCAM) (Box 3)
  - Douglas R. Hofstadter Analogy as the Core of Cognition Stanford Humanities Center Presidential Lecture, February 6, 2006., V251.31; 1 optical disc (DVD) (Box 3)